import 'package:my_protfolio1/model/question.dart';
import 'package:my_protfolio1/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. What is the capital of Basngladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Chittagong',
      'b) Dhaka',
      'c) Rajshahi',
      'd) Sylhet',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. In what continent is Bangladesh located?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Europe',
      'b) Asia',
      'c) North America',
      'd) South Asia',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. What is the largest planet in our solar system?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Earth',
      'b) Jupiter',
      'c) Saturn',
      'd) Venus',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. What is the longest sea beach in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Bay of Bengal',
      'b) Amazon',
      'c) Mississippi',
      'd) Danube',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Who is the main character in the John wick movie series?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Hermione Granger',
      'b) Ron Weasley',
      'c) Keneu Rives',
      'd) Neville Longbottom',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. What is the smallest bird?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Parrot',
      'b) Sparrow',
      'c) Doyel',
      'd) Hamim bird',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. What is the highest mountain in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Mont Blanc',
      'b) Aconcagua',
      'c) Kilimanjaro',
      'd) Everest',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. Who wrote the play Romeo and Juliet?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) William Shakespeare',
      'b) Oscar Wilde',
      'c) Jane Austen',
      'd) Charles Dickens',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '9. What is the name of the famous painting by Leonardo da Vinci that depicts a woman?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Starry Night',
      'b) The Persistence of Memory',
      'c) The Last Supper',
      'd) Mona Lisa',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '10. What is the name of the famous all rounder in cricket for not only Bangladesh but also accross the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Starry Night',
      'b) The Persistence of Memory',
      'c) The Last Supper',
      'd) Mona Lisa',
    ],
  ),
];
